Yerbol Palzhanov

 $\begin{array}{ccc} {\rm Research~Scientist,~PhD} \\ +1~713~820~1919 & {\rm palzhanov@gmail.com} \end{array}$

ABOUT ME

Dedicated professional with a strong background in scientific software development, specializing in C++ for numerical linear algebra, numerical analysis, and finite element methods. Contributed to a C++ finite element package with 5 peer-reviewed journal publications. Experienced in parallel programming, MPI, OpenMP, CUDA, machine learning for physics, and deep learning using TensorFlow.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2023	Ph.D in Computational Science, University of Houston, Houston, TX
	thesis: Numerical finite element methods for phase field equations
	advisors: M. Olshanskii; A. Quaini
2015 - 2017	M.S. in Mathematics, Atyrau State University, Atyrau, Kazakhstan
	thesis: Numerical methods based on energy minimization principle for computing thermal fields
	advisor: B. Kenzhegulov
2008 - 2012	B.S. in Mathematics, Auezov University, Shymkent, Kazakhstan

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

My profile at Google scholar.

- 3. A scalar auxiliary variable unfitted FEM for the surface Cahn-Hilliard equation, M. Olshanskii, Y. Palzhanov, A. Quaini – Journal of Scientific Computing, Oct 2023
- 2. Lipid domain coarsening and fluidity in multicomponent vesicles: A continuum model and its experimental validation, Y. Wang, Y. Palzhanov, A. Quaini, M. Olshanskii, S. Majd BBA Biomembranes, 2022
- A decoupled, stable, and linear FEM for a phase-field model of variable density two-phase incompressible surface flow,
 Y. Palzhanov, A. Zhiliakov, A. Quaini, M. Olshanskii Computer Methods in Applied Mechanics and Eng., 2021

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Researcher @ University Of Houston

2019 - 2024

- Developing Navier–Stokes–Cahn–Hilliard model for two-phase surface flows
 - Contributed to finite element C++ package DROPS CFD tool for simulating two-phase flows to model flows
 - Integrated the collection of scientific software libraries Trilinos(BELOS, AMESOS2, EPETRA) to solve systems of linear equations with Flexible GMRES
 - Tools & Frameworks: C++, MPI, Trilinos, Parallel Computing, Linux, CMAKE, GIT, Paraview
- Modeling and experimenting with multicomponent lipid vesicles
 - Implemented unconditionally energy stable scalar auxiliary variable algorithm for phase field equations
 - Studied fusogenicity of positively charged lipid vesicles via thermodynamically consistent NSCH H-model
 - Tools & Frameworks: MATLAB, Python, DROPS, Cluster & Cloud Computing
- Reduced order modeling with Convolutional Autoencoders, LSTM, and Transformers
 - Developed convolutional autoencoder neural network for order reduction of advection-dominated 2D flows
 - Implemented LSTM for temporal evolution prediction of rising thermal bubble
 - Tools & Frameworks: OpenFoam, Tensorflow, Cluster & Cloud Computing

Academic Vice-Principal @ Bilim-Innovation Lyceums

2012 - 2019

- Trained national IMO(International mathematics olympiads) team members, best result: gold medalist.
- Served as an academic vice-principal in Atyrau BIL, listed in TOP-5 schools in Kazakhstan.

CERTIFICATES

TensorFlow Developer certificate

Hands-on four-course Professional Certificate program, on Convolutional Neural Networks, Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Time Series Analysis in Tensorflow.

CONFERENCES & TALKS

4. Talk @ 6th Annual Meeting of the SIAM Texas-Louisiana Section Topic: A scalar auxiliary variable unfitted FEM for the surface Cahn-Hilliard equation University of Louisiana, Lafayette, LA, November 3-5, 2023

3. Talk @ 5th Annual Meeting of the SIAM Texas-Louisiana Section University Of Houston, Houston, TX, November 4-6, 2022

2. Talk @ Graduate Student Paper Presentation (GSPP)
Topic: Simulating lipid domain coarsening with TraceFEM
University Of Houston, Houston, TX, April 29, 2022

1. Talk @ SMU Finite Element Rodeo

Topic: Finite Element Methods for Surface Navier-Stokes-Cahn-Hilliard Equations Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX, March 4-5, 2022